# Ion Para

## Full Stack Web Developer



+44 7882241476



para\_ion@hotmail.com



https://linkedin.com/in/ionpara-934261211/



https://github.com/lonPara



https://ionpara.com



https://www.hyperiondev.co m/portfolio/107300/

### **Tech Skills**

- Frontend web development in HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- ☑ Single-page application development with React.js
- ☑ Full stack application development with MERN stack
- Web API integration
- Object-oriented programming
- Source version control
- ☑ Git & GitHub

## **Soft Skills**

- Time management
- Adaptability
- Problem solving
- Critical thinking

## Languages

English

Romanian

Russian

## **Hobbies and Interests**

Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu, Stock Market, Roller Skating, Personal Growth and Self Development



A full stack web developer currently seeking junior or graduate web development roles. Possesses strong work ethics, commitment, dedication and able to work in high-pressure and challenging environments. Previous experience of working in a team for over six years as well as possessing a strong self directed learning skill which was developed while studying software development.

# **Experience**

#### Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

Dec 2022- Mar 2023

Dec 2022- Mar 2023

Sep 2012- Jun 2016

HyperionDev, Remote

Functions and responsibilities:

- Work on a portfolio of 62 tasks
- Built projects using front-end technologies such as JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React.
- Built projects using back-end technologies such as Node.js and Express.js
- Built full-stack application projects using the MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js) stack.
- Troubleshot given programs, identified issues, and provided solutions.

## Projects

Portfolio Project (React, CSS, React-Bootstrap, Tailwind): https://ionpara.com/

Just Read (MERN, CSS, Tailwind, Google books API): https://just-read.netlify.app/

This app contains a books store. The app allows for the user to login / signup and search for his / her favourite book, purchase a book and leave a review.

Hangman Game (JavaScript, React.js, CSS): https://hangman-game-101.netlify.app/

This project contains the "Hangman" game. The goal of this project is to consolidate all previously learned concepts about building web applications with React, JSX and JavaScript.

Just Fight (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript): https://ionpara.github.io/Just-Fight/

This project contains a website built to showcase a hobby, the goal is to provide information about the experience working on the front-end side using object-oriented design.

### Education

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

HyperionDev, Remote

Management in Tourism - National College

of Viticulture and Winemaking

Chisinau, Republic of Moldova



## **Courses and Certificates**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Git & GitHub - Codecademy 2021-2022